In this lecture, I'm going to do a console walkthrough of Amazon bedrock agents so that
you can visually see what are the capabilities that the bedrock agents offer.
Now let's go ahead and head over to the console.
So I'm on the AWS console.
Let me just search for Amazon bedrock and here I have Amazon bedrock, okay.
I'm going to go on the left hand side and under the builder tools, I have agents.
Let me just click on agents and I'm on the agents homepage.
Now let me just go ahead and click on this create agent.
And here we have to provide the name of the agent.
So let's just say we're creating a flight booking agent.
Then you can provide a description of what this agent does.
This is optional, so we'll just leave it as it is.
Next we have an important thing here called as multi agent collaboration.
In one of the previous lectures, we'll learn that we can either build a single agent or
if our application is really complex, then we can have multi agent scenario.
So now if we just click on this enable multi agent collaboration and click on create, you'll
be able to use the multi agent framework.
And we're going to build this use case a little later.
But for now, let me just focus on single agent and let me just click on create.
Okay, now this agent flight booking agent was successfully created.
Now let's just go through some of the other attributes related to this agent.
So first we have agent details, so agent name, which we've already provided.
Then you have the agent description, which is optional.
So next you have the agent resource role, so now our agent will need to interact with
different AWS services, maybe an AWS Lambda knowledge basis S3 bucket.
So the agent requires an IM role, which enables it to call these different AWS services.
For that, you need a service role.
So either you can create one by yourself through the IM service and then it will be enabled
here or you can just tell the agent to create the role for you.
And that's what we're going to do.
Next we have to select a large language model that is going to drive the agent.
So if we just click on this select model and if I just see here on the top, if I just
uncheck this, you'll see it supports all the major models.
But when I just click on this, I can see only two, one is the Amazon and here are the models
that it supports and then you have the entropic and these are the model it supports from
entropic.
So the reason is that when we build agents, it needs some default prompt templates to enable
the reasoning capability for the model.
And for now, AWS has these default templates only for these two model providers.
But if you want to use, let's say, Mistral, then you have to write your own customized
prompt template.
So that's why we'll just go with one of these two.
Now just remember if you're using the models from Amazon, then right now it does not support
the long term memory.
So if you need long term memory, then you have to use one of the models from entropic.
If you don't have access to models, just click on this request access and you can also
just go from here to model access and then.
So you'll see a screen like this model access from here, just click on modify access and
then select all the models you want access to, just scroll down, click on next and then
do a submit and you should have access to models.
But just remember entropic is limiting access to personal accounts.
You might face challenges in terms of getting access to a particular model or number of requests
you can make per second.
So if you don't need the long term memory, just select one model from Amazon, maybe no
approach, that's that's really good.
Okay, then next, you need to provide instructions for the agent and this is really important
because it defines the domain of the agent.
So if you're a flight booking agent, then let's say we're going to give a detailed description.
You are an airline booking agent and can do following things, answer queries related
to flight availability, query and display, flight availability for a particular date,
book of flight and so on.
So you need to be as descriptive as possible.
And in the next lecture, I'll tell you why the instructions are so important.
Okay.
Next, I'll just click on this additional settings.
And next, you can see code interpreter and code interpreter enables agents to handle tasks
that involve writing, running, testing and troubleshooting code in a secure environment.
So if you just click enabled, what it will do is it will provide a secure sandbox where
the agent, if it needs to fix an issue, it can go ahead and generate code, run that code
in the secure environment and then apply.
Next you have the user input.
Now let's say you're a flight booking agent and the user has given you details on booking
a flight from New York to Chicago on a particular date.
But as an agent, you found multiple flights, one that's a direct flight and then one flight,
which is one stop.
And the user has not provided whether he wants a direct flight or one stop flight.
So in that case, if you enable this, then the agent can go ahead and ask a clarifying
question to the end user.
And if you keep it disabled, then it will just make an assumption and go ahead and process
that request.
Next you have the KMS.
So if you want to encrypt your data, you can use the KMS service.
Next you have the idle session timeout.
So this is mainly the short term memory of the agent.
So you can determine the duration for which you need to keep the session active between
the end user and the agent.
So once it has reached that limit of let's say 600 seconds idle session timeout and
there is no interaction between the user and the agent, then it's going to close that session.
So that means you'll lose the short term memory.
And next we have the action groups.
So you can think of action groups as tools that you can integrate with your bedrock agents.
So for our example, let's say for a flight booking agent, you might have a tool which
takes the input from the end user like source destination date of travel name of the traveler
and then takes that data and makes an API call to the airline database to reserve a flight
for our end user.
So now if I just click on add and you have to provide the interaction group name, the description.
Now when you are adding an action group that integrates with the bedrock agent, there are
two things you need to keep in mind.
First you have to define the action group type and then action group invocation.
So let me first talk about action group invocation.
So it's just the lambda function that you would write your logic in which will make that
API call to the airline database.
So either you can create a new lambda function or you can select an existing lambda function
that you might have already written.
So that's the action group invocation.
The first is the action group type.
Now before the agent executes this action group, it needs certain guidance on what will
be the input parameters that will be passed by the user.
So in our case, maybe source destination, date of travel and name of the user.
So we have to define that somewhere and what is the response, maybe a booking ID.
So you define those input and output parameters.
So there are agent and execute the task better.
And this is what action group type is used for.
So when you select define with function details, so you can just go down and here you
see the parameters and here you just click on add parameters and add the parameters like
what is the user input going to look like.
So source destination name of the traveler and date.
So you define those parameters.
So it's much simpler when you use define with functionality detail.
Next, the other option that you have is use the APA schema.
So when I just click on this APA schema and you have two options, you have action group schema
here.
So select an existing APA schema.
So if you already written and it can be written simple YAML.
So you already written that and you upload it on the S3 bucket or you can do it where
inline schema editor.
So if I just click on this and this is what it's going to look like.
So it simply defines what are the input parameters that the user is going to provide.
And those input parameters then would be utilized within the lambda function and then the
lambda function is going to make a call.
You're going to get a response and that response is going to be passed to the agent.
So that's all you define here.
And we're going to create all this in lot of detail.
So if you haven't understood, it's okay.
I'm just trying to give a high level overview on how these things work.
Okay.
Now that we have learned about action groups next, we have the memory.
So this memory is a long term memory that bedrock agents enables for your use case.
So by default, it's disabled, but once you click on enable, it will tell you for how long
you want to store that long term memory.
So it can be anywhere between one to 365 days and you can also define number of session.
So maybe instead of the duration, you can define the number of sessions you want to maintain.
And next you have the knowledge bases.
So you can think of nauseous again as tools that you can integrate with your bedrock agents
which provide you manage rag based capability.
So what you can do is you can go on your left and you can see here bedrock knowledge bases.
If I just click on that and here you can create your knowledge bases.
And once you have created that knowledge bases, you can go back to the bedrock agent and
just click on add and then select the knowledge bases that you have created from here and
it will be integrated with your agent.
Again, we are going to build the knowledge bases and integrate when we come to our use cases.
So don't worry about this.
Then you have guard rail details.
If you go on the left, you have safe guards, guard rail details.
If I just click on this and here we have guard rails.
So you can go ahead, create guard rails and once you have created a guard rail.
So I have these guard rails here and if I just click and click on this edit and if I just
select, you can select the guard rails that you have created.
Again, we are going to create this as part of our use case, but I just wanted to show you
what are the capabilities and how you can integrate with the agents.
Okay, next we have the orchestration strategy, specify how the agent processes information
and coordinates a response by default, orchestration is defined by advanced prompts that can
be overridden or customized for advanced use case.
So you can either use default orchestration prompts based on the large language model that
you have selected or you can write your own.
So we just click on this edit and you can see these orchestration templates here.
So you can see for pre-processing, orchestration, knowledge base and then you have one more
post-processing and if you just click on this orchestration, we have the override orchestration
template defaults.
So you can override and write your own, but we just go to the continue with the default
ones and here prompt template editor.
So these are some of the instructions that are sent to the large language model along
with the user query and if you see here.
So it's telling the large language model on how to process the user input and here you
can see it says in the thought first answer the following question, what is the user's goal?
What information has just been provided?
What is the best action plan or step by step action to fulfill the user's request?
So how does this help?
It basically helps in chain of thought and reasoning and action planning step for the agent.
So let's say the user has sent a query, book up flight for me with following detail.
So what the large language model driving the agent is going to do is it's going to break
down that user tasks into these seven steps.
So what's the user goal to book a flight?
What information has been provided?
So he's providing me the name, date, source, destination.
What is the best action plan?
So it will break down that user request into multiple steps that didn't take maybe make
a call to the airline booking database and so on.
So this is what an orchestration prompt does.
Similarly, you have one for the knowledge base.
So if there is a request related to the knowledge basis, how that is going to be executed
and then you have the post processing, which defines how the agent determined the final
response.
So if we just click on cancel and then finally we have the multi agent collaboration.
So when we want to have multiple agents as part of a application, then you will use this
multi agent collaboration.
So if we just click on this edit.
So here it shows collaboration status.
So if I just enable this multi agent collaboration, then first you define what is going
to be a supervisor agent.
So in a multi agent scenario, you'll at least have three agents.
So you'll have two agents who will be specialized agents or in other terms, they are called
as collaborator agents, they will be the worker agents.
And then you will have a supervisor agent, which takes the request from the end user and
then determines based on certain criteria, which agent it can forward that request to.
And here we select the supervisor agent.
And then we have the specialized agent or collaborator agents as they are called.
So you can select which collaborator agent you want to use.
Okay, that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I just wanted to give you a high level overview of the capabilities of the Amazon bedrock agents.
If you're not understood some of the aspects in detail, it's okay where I'm going to
reiterate and we're going to build all these capabilities when we go to the hands on use
cases.
I'll see in the next lecture, thank you.